See this glowing dot?
That's the whole universe.
Let me show you why.
This is a black hole.
And this bright ring is hot gas,
spinning around it.
Let's look at it from above.
See?
The disk is actually flat.
This is the back half.
And this is the front half.
Now watch the back half,
as we go back down.
The black hole bends its light,
up over the top...
and under the bottom.
Now let's fly in closer.
Much closer.
If you hover right here,
the black hole fills
exactly half your sky.
And see this thin line?
That's light,
going around the black hole in a circle.
Light can go all the way around...
and come back to you.
So in this line,
you see the back of your own head.
Now let's go lower,
and hover just above the edge.
Then look up.
The whole universe shrinks
into one small dot above you.
And down here,
time runs slower.
Stay for one minute...
and half an hour goes by out there.
And all this darkness around the dot?
That's the black hole.